CURRICULUM VITAE

SUNIL KUMAR

HNo: 45-B, Surajpur Site-C, Near Jagat Farm, Greater Noida-201306 Mob No: 9389748919 / 9193945657 E-mail: sunilcareerplus@amail.com



Summary:

7+ Years of overall experience working in Devops, Private Cloud Data Security, Multi-Cloud & Data-warehouse Technologies. While, **4 years of experience** in the field of DevOps Engineer in CI/CD Pipeline configurations, Code Compilation, Packaging, Building, Automating, Managing and releasing Code from development environment to production environment. Experienced in Jenkins implementation, configuration & maintaining for purpose of continuous integration and for end to end automation for all code build & deployments and **Creating Jenkins CI/CD pipelines with CircleCI & Terraform.** "Strong analytical and problem-solving skills and can work either independently with little or no supervision or as a member of a team."

Job Experience:

- ► Two Year experience as a System Administrator in IT Department of OnSpot Technical Services Pvt. Ltd Noida from 3rd -Jun-2013 to 10th -July-2015.
- ► Three Year experience as a Linux Administrator in the IT Department of CloudnCare Technologies Pvt. Ltd Gurgaon-122018 from 25th July-2015 to 30th Mar-2019.
- ► Two Year experience as a Sr. Devops Engineer in the IT Department of Abhay Technos Services Pvt. Ltd Gurgaon-122001 from 26th -Apr-2019 to till date.

Professional Qualification & Certifications:

- BSc-IT Passed from Punjab Technical University Jalandhar-144603.
- Kubernetes Certified administrator from Udemy Academy Online Training.
- Certified Multi-Cloud Networking & Security from Aviatrix (ACE) Online Training.
- AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner Essentials from AWS Online Certifications Training.
- AWS Certified SysOps Administrator Associate from Udemy Academy Online Training.

Planning, Implementation, Configuration Windows & Linux Server Technical Skills:

- ® Managing, Implementation & Configuration Dedicated IIS 8.0 Web Server & MS SQL Database Server 2012/2016 on Windows Server Platform: Windows-2008/2012-R2 & Windows-2016 R2 etc.
- ® Write Bash & Shell Scripting for Generate Automate Task Like: System Optimization & Automatic Server File & Directory Incremental Backup on Remote Locations: FTP, NAS & Azure Cloud etc.
- ® Write Python Automation Scripting for Automate Each Task Like: Time Scheduling AWS EC2-Instances Start/Stop, Creating CI/CD Pipeline Infrastructure & Send Bulk Mail Notification Alert etc.
- ® Planning, Installation & Configuration Apache LAMP Web Server, Tomcat Application Web Server and JBoss Application Server on Linux OS: RHEL-7 & CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc
- ® Implementation Configuration & Managing Multiple Dedicated Web-Hosting Server through using WHM cPanel, aaPanel, & CyberPanel on Linux Platform: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Managing, Configuration & Deployment Server less Containerization Technologies like: Vmware-16 Virtual Machine, Docker Container Platform v17 on Linux Cloud Platforms: CentOS-7 & Ubuntu etc.
- ® Planning, Implementation & Configuration Kubernetes Cluster Architecture & Ingress controller, Managing & Monitoring Containerized Workloads, and Deploy Kubernetes-Helm & Pods, Master & Worker Node through Kubeadm on Multi-Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7, Ubuntu-18.0 etc.

Managing, Designing & Configuration Day-to-Day Role & Responsibilities:

- ® Planning, Implementation & Maintaining AWS Cloud Architecture through Various Amazon Web Services like: Amazon EC2, Amazon S3 Bucket, Amazon EFS, Amazon EBS, Amazon IAM, Amazon VPC, AWS Route53 & WAF on AWS Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Installation & Configuration Various Amazon Web Services Like: Amazon RDS, Amazon Cogito, AWS Elastic Beanstalk, Amazon CloudFormation, Amazon Lambda, Amazon CloudWatch, Amazon Systems Manager & AWS CDK on AWS Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Amazon Linux etc.
- ® Planning, Installation & Configuration Amazon Private Cloud Data Security Services like: Amazon Security Groups, AWS Security Hub, AWS Secrets Manager, Amazon Inspector, Amazon MFA & KMS, AWS GuardDuty & CloudTrail on Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18 etc.
- ® Maintain, Installation & Configuration AWS Management Services Like: Amazon EC2 Autoscaling, Elastic Container Service (ECS), Amazon Elastic Kubernetes Service (EKS) & Amazon API Gateway on AWS Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Amazon Linux 3.0 etc.
- ® Planning, Installation Configuration Various Load Balancing AWS Services Like: Application Load Balancer (ALB), Network Load Balancer (NLB) & Elastic Load Balancing (ELB) on AWS Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Deploying, Maintaining & Configuration Creating Automate Time-Scheduling AWS EC2 Backup & Amazon RDS SQL Backups through using Data Lifecycle Manager on AWS Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® AWS Billing Cost Optimization, Automate Analyzing AWS Billing Data through using billing Saving Techniques: AWS S3 Intelligent Tiering Without interrupting AWS Services.

- ® Managing, Designing & Configuration Infrastructure as a Code Architectures Like: Creating Jenkins build job & CI/CD Pipeline Infrastructure through using Terraform with CircleCI, Git & Github on Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Planning, Implementation & Creating Jenkins CI/CD Pipeline Infrastructure through using Groovy Pipeline Scripting with Maven, Git & GitHub on Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Managing, Implementation & Deploying Jenkins CI/CD Pipeline Infrastructure through using Terraform, Docker Container with Bamboo, Git & GitHub on AWS EC2-Linux Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Planning, Implementation & Configuration Amazon RDS Infrastructure for Various Database Services Like: Amazon Aurora, MySQL, MariaDB, PostgreSQL, DynamoDB & MS SQL Database Server on Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Managing & Configuration AWS Redshift Infrastructure & Deployment Amazon Redshift Spectrum, Workload Management (WLM) for Advanced Monitoring & Performance Tuning on AWS Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Planning, Implementation & Deploy Azure infrastructure and Creating Azure Linux Virtual Machine, Create Virtual Network with Network Security Group through using Hashicorp Terraform on Azure Linux Cloud Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 LTS etc.
- ® Implementation, Configuration, Maintaining & Creating Web Services like: Azure Virtual Machine, Azure Disk Storage, Azure EKS & ECS, Azure load balancing, Azure Database, Azure ExpressRoute, Azure Dedicated Host, & WAF on Azure Linux Platforms: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18.04 etc.
- ® Deployment & Configuration Dedicated Centralized Scheduling Cloud Backup Server for Online Multi-Cloud Storage Services: Amazon S3, Azure Cloud & Google Cloud etc.
- ® Implementation & Configuration Monitoring Tools like: Nagios Core, Datadog, Grafana & Prometheus for Multi-Cloud Services Performance Monitoring on Linux OS: RHEL-7, CentOS-7 & Ubuntu-18 etc.
- ® Planning, Implementation & Manage Your Multi-Cloud Access Secrets, Sensitive Data Secrets & Application Secrets and Protect Hard-Coded Credentials (e.g. Passwords, API keys, SSH Keys & RSA Tokens etc.) through using HashiCorp Vault from One Centralized Workflow Location.

Check My Current Live Devops Project: ATechnos Launches a Premium Online Cloud based Gaming platform. Please visit to more info: https://gogames.run & https://mtn.gogames.run/

DECLARATION:

T 1 1	1 1	that infor			1		1		. 1	1 .	C	1 1	1
Inarant	7 MACIARA	that intai	matian	α ition '	าทกงหกา	IRA FRIIA	าทสเ	CORPORT TO	tha	nact a	tmi	IZMATA	$\alpha \alpha \alpha \alpha$
1 1161611	/ ucciaic	tilat lilloi	mation	2175116	auuvca	แธนนธ	anu c	.011566 10	unc	บธระบ	'I IIIV	KIIUVVI	cugc.
				O- · ·							,		

Date: Sunil Ku	mar
----------------	-----